Guide to the Seventh Regiment Fund Court Case Records 1950–2010 (bulk, 1996-2007) MS 3032
New-York Historical Society
Seventh Regiment Fund court case records
1950–2010 (bulk, 1996-2007)
New-York Historical Society
Seventh Regiment Fund
MS 3032
3 Linear feet (3 record cartons)
A small collection of legal documents accompanying a 1996 lawsuit brought by New York's Attorney General against the Seventh Regiment Fund over ownership of the artwork, objects, and memorabilia housed in the Seventh Regiment Armory at 643 Park Avenue, Manhattan. A 2006 ruling decided in favor of New York State's ownership of the material.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Seventh Regiment Fund, July 2017.
Historical Note
The Seventh Regiment, known as the "silk stocking regiment" for its well-heeled members, descends from four volunteer militia companies organized in 1806 to protect New York from attack by the British. The Seventh Regiment, along with other military and social organizations, has been housed since 1880 in the massive armory at 643 Park Avenue, which incorporates rooms for company offices, a library, galleries, and a block-long drill hall. The Armory's interiors were designed by such Gilded Age giants as Louis Comfort Tiffany and Stanford White.
The Seventh Regiment Fund was incorporated in 1909 "to promote and conserve the interests and welfare of the Seventh Regiment, National Guard, New York, and its successors, and to that end and for those purposes to take and hold by gift, bequest, purchase or lease, either absolutely or in trust, real or personal property, to apply the same and the income, rents, issues and profits, derived from the investment thereof, for the purposes aforesaid, in such manner and at such times as the Board of Directors may from time to time direct."
By their interpretation, the Seventh Regiment Fund controlled the contents of the armory, and could dispose of them with impunity. But in 1996, New York Attorney General Dennis C. Vacco filed suit against the Seventh Regiment Fund, charging that its directors had illegally assumed title to the artifacts in their care, and had possibly lost or sold many of them without turning over proceeds to the state. In 2006 a judge ruled in favor of New York State's ownership of the disputed memorabilia.
Arrangement
With minor exceptions, the records are filed in the order imposed by the donor. Clarifying titles [in brackets] were supplied by the archivist.
Related Archival Materials
The New-York Historical Society holds the Records of the 7th Regiment 1767-1983, as well as the 9,000-volume Seventh Regiment Military Library, the titles from which may be found in the N-YHS Library Catalog.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Scope and Contents
This small collection documents the 1996 lawsuit brought by New York Attorney General Dennis C. Vacco against the Seventh Regiment Fund and other involved parties, disputing ownership of the artifacts, artwork, memorabilia, etc., housed in the Seventh Regiment Armory (643 Park Avenue) and charged to have been lost or illegally disposed of by the Seventh Regiment Fund. It includes object lists, pleading files and other court papers, printed by-laws of the Seventh Regiment Fund, newspaper clippings, and copies of legal research and supporting material.
Armories -- New York (State) -- New York.; Regiments -- 7th New York State Militia.; Seventh Regiment Armory (New York, N.Y.)
- Guide to the Records of the 7th Regiment 1767–1983, 2004 May 10 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  A bound printout of the finding aid to the 7th Regiment records housed at the New-York Historical Society. For the latest version see http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/7threg/.
- [Object list: Complete Database List], n.d. (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  Contents of a 3-section binder labeled "Master Notebook I":
  Missing Title
  Armory List
  Objects on loan
  Room lists
- [Object list: gallery 111], n.d. (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
- [Object list: gallery 112—Colonel's Reception Room], n.d. (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
- [Object list: gallery 113—Veteran's Room], n.d. (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
- [Object list: gallery 114A—Curator's Office], n.d. (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
- [Object list: missing and problematic] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  Contents of a 4-section binder:
  Objects Not Appraised
  Missing Objects
  Objects Not Photographed
  Object Problems
- Pleading files: Supreme Court of The State of New York (Index No. 103638/06) [5 folders], 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8–12)
  In the Matter of the Application of Rita C. Chu, The Seventh Regiment Fund and The Veterans of the Seventh Regiment v. NY State Urban Development Corp. d/b/a Empire State Development Corp and Seventh Regiment Armory Conservancy, Inc.
- Pleading files: Supreme Court of The State of New York (Index No. 406660/96) [21 folders], 1996 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1-21)
  The State of New York v. The Seventh Regiment Fund, Inc., and The Members of the Board of Directors of the Seventh Regiment Fund, Inc., individually and as Directors, The Members of the Board of Officers of the 107th Infantry Regiment, New York National Guard, a/k/a The HHC, 107th Brigade, a/k/a The HHC, 205th Support Group, individually.
- Pleading files: Supreme Court of The State of New York, Appellate Division (Index No. 406660/96) [4 folders], 1998–2002 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1-4)
  The State of New York v. The Seventh Regiment Fund, Inc., and The Members of the Board of Directors of the Seventh Regiment Fund, Inc., individually and as Directors, The Members of the Board of Officers of the 107th Infantry Regiment, New York National Guard, a/k/a THE HHC, 107th Brigade, a/k/a THE HHC, 205th Support Group, individually.
- Pleading files: Supreme Court of the State of New York, County of Albany (Index No. 122330/97) [2 folders], 1997–2001 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5-6)
  Seventh Regiment Fund, Inc. v. The Adjutant General, Division of Military and Naval Affairs.
- Complaint: United States District Court Southern District of New York (Index No. 01civ0819), 2001 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
  The Seventh Regiment Fund, Associates of the Engineer Corps and Company K, Seventh Regiment, Inc., and the Veterans of the Seventh Regiment v. George Pataki, et al.
- Memorandum of Law In Support of Preliminary Injunction and Temporary Restraining Order (Index No. 17465/05), 2005 December 6 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
  Supreme Court of New York—County of New York—David L. Dalva II, v. George Pataki, et al.
- Pleading files: Supreme Court of New York, County of New York (Index No. 116965/05) [3 folders], 2005 December 6–2007 October 2 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9-11)
  David L. Dalva II, v. George Pataki, et. al.
- Summons: Supreme Court of New York, County of New York (Index No. 115703/05), 2005 November 11 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12)
  The Seventh Regiment Fund v. Joseph Clark.
- Brief for Plaintiff-Appellant and Record on Appeal (Docket Nos. 09-02448 and 09-02449) (Oneida County Clerk's Index No. 2002-000808) [4 folders], 2010 April 12 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 13-16)
  New York Supreme Court—Appellate Division—Fourth Department—Utica Mutual Insurance Co. v. McAteer & Fitzgerald, Inc. and Kenyon B. Fitzgerald, an individual v. Michael McAteer, an individual
- Seventh Regiment Fund constitution and by-laws, 1950, 1985, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
- Tobin / LaGuardia Record on Appeal, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
- Legal Research / Tobin Cases, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
- Chapter 932 of Laws of New York, 1942 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
- Legislative History—Chapter 932 of Laws of New York, 1942, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 21)
- [Newspaper clippings and press releases], 1996–1999 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 22)
- The Seventh Regiment Fund / Trustees—Client Documents (Offsite-box 3, Folder 23)
- [Military Code of the State of New York], n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 24)
- The Seventh Regiment Fund / New York State Motion for Reargument Research [2 folders] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 25–26)
- [loose documents], n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 27)